Phuc Nguyen

Product Designer with 3+ years of experience specializing in crafting user-centric, objective-driven digital applications to help startups in Health and Fitness, Finance, and Social Networking achieve their milestones.

San Jose, CA | (408) 229-3278 phuchnguyen.design@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/phucngyn www.p-nguyen.com

SKILLS

- Figma
- Figjam
- Design System
- User-centric Design
- Visual Design
- Dev Handoff
- Accessibility Design

- UX Research
- Product Management
- Strategies
- Storyboarding
- User Journey
- User Flows
- Prototyping

- Wireframing
- Agile Development
- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- Web / Mobile (iOS & Android)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Product Designer

myBook | San Jose, CA

May 2024 - Present

- Organized and facilitated daily standup meetings via JIRA and Confluence to track project health, documentation, and roadblocks, to ensure alignment of team goals, communication, and productivity of cross-functional teams.
- Led the research and design efforts for mobile applications on both iOS and Android platforms, ensuring a seamless user experience and alignment with market needs.
- Implemented a custom design system for a two-person Engineering team, streamlining the translation of wireframes and mockups and enhancing collaboration across cross-functional teams.

Product Designer

Checkbook.io | San Mateo, CA

July 2021 - September 2023

- Spearheaded a complete overhaul and redesign of the company's external API endpoint documentation to enhance accessibility and usability for developers and non-developers, resulting in a 30% reduction in daily technical support inquiries.
- Led the research, design, and implementation process of a new payment product, Virtual Credit Card, which introduced a legally compliant and versatile payment solution that increased the user base by 15% and enabled them to issue over \$4 million quarterly.
- Facilitated cross-functional meetings among internal teams and clients to create white-labeled solutions in line with client brand specifications and legal requirements, ensuring successful implementations and concise end products.
- Coordinated a variety of successful marketing campaigns and designed over 50 graphic assets for various channels, including ad banners, email graphics, and social media posts, significantly boosting brand identity, visibility, and engagement.
- Partnered with internal Sales and Engineering teams to strategically plan and implement Google Analytics, enabling comprehensive tracking of user engagement metrics and enhancing data-driven decision-making processes.

Product Designer

Cohart | Remote

December 2020 - April 2021

• Collaborated with key cross-functional stakeholders, including co-founders, engineers, and marketing, to develop the roadmap for the Alpha launch of principal products.

EDUCATION

San Jose State University

BA | Graphic Design

PROJECTS

Run Tracker Mubi